gov.uk 2003-08-14

# Privacy policy

This page explains how ukonline.gov.uk, which is managed by the Cabinet Office, uses any information you give to us, and the ways in which we protect your privacy.

**The Data Protection Act**

Under the Data Protection Act, we have a legal duty to protect any information we collect from you. We use leading technologies and encryption software to safeguard your data, and keep strict security standards to prevent any unauthorised access to it. We do not pass on your details to any third party or government department unless you give us permission to do so. 

**What information do we collect?**

We collect three kinds of information from visitors to ukonline.gov.uk: registration information, feedback (through emails to the Editor) and site usage information, from cookies and log files. 

_1 Registration information_

You do not have to register to use ukonline.gov.uk, but you do need to register to take part in Forums. 

The registration information we collect is: your username (which does not need to be your real name), a password, a postcode (if you wish to give us one) and your email address. Our technology supplier, Loudcloud, stores this information securely. Loudcloud keeps it so that you do not need to re-register when you come back to the site. This information is also stored on back-up tapes to avoid loss of data. We do not use this information to trace your identity and do not pass it on to any third party or government department. 

_2 Feedback_

We welcome your feedback. You can contact us by emailing editor@ukonline.gov.uk. 

_i) Comments and questions_

If you send an email or letter to the Editor, asking for information, we may need to contact other government departments to find that information. If your question is technical, we may need to pass it to our technology suppliers. We do not pass on any of your personal information when dealing with your enquiry, unless you have given us permission to do so. Once we have replied to you, we keep a record of your messages for six months for reference and audit purposes, after which it is deleted. 

_ii) Forums_

Any comments you add to Forums can be viewed by all users and are stored securely by Loudcloud. Your registered username will appear next to your comments. 

We will not publish comments which break our forum rules. 

Loudcloud stores comments in the same way as "Registration information", as detailed above. 

_3 Site usage information_

_i) Cookies_

Cookies are pieces of data that are often created when you visit a website, and which are stored in the cookie directory of your computer. Three cookies are created when you visit ukonline. 

Our first cookie stores a random number on your computer to help us count the number of times users return to our site. The second cookie is used to store some of your preferences while you move around the site. This cookie is deleted when you leave the site. The third cookie is part of a project to share banner advertising for government campaigns and services across government websites. It stores a random number to ensure that you do not always see the same advert and it enables us to count the number of people viewing a web page or a campaign. This cookie is checked when you visit other government websites involved in the same project. 

The cookies do not contain any personal information about you, and they cannot be used to identify an individual user. 

You can set your browser not to accept cookies but if you do this you will not be able to log in or change your regional preference. 

_ii) Log files_

Log files allow us to record visitors' use of the site. Loudcloud and Digimine, a data research company, analyse log file information from all our visitors, which we use to make changes to the layout of the site and to the information in it, based on the way that visitors move around it. 

Log files do not contain any personal information and they are not used to identify any individual patterns of use of the site. 

**What happens when I link to another site?**

ukonline.gov.uk contains links to other websites, both those of government departments and of other organisations. This privacy policy applies only to our site, so you should always be aware when you are moving to another site and read the privacy statement of any site which collects personal information. 

We do not pass on any personal information you have given us to any other site. 

**Access to your information and contacting ukonline.gov.uk**

You can change your registration information at any time. To do this, you should sign in then click to "Edit your details" on the homepage. 

If you wish to see our records of any correspondence you have sent to us, or if you have a query or complaint about this privacy policy or about the site, you can contact us by email: 

editor@ukonline.gov.uk 

**Changes to this privacy policy**

If this privacy policy changes in any way, we will place an updated version on this page. Regularly reviewing this page ensures you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances, if any, we will share it with other parties.
